Finding Aid for the Yvar Mikhashoff Collection of Annotated Scores, 1828-1993
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Annotated scores 1762-1993, I.; Folder 001-Folder 607
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Boris Baranovic: whirling, 1984, 1 score (1 leaf); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains fingerings marked in red ink. Found in folder labeled Virgil Thomson: The Last Portraits. (Box 24, Folder 0521)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Cradle of Gertrude Stein or Mysteries in the Rue de Fleurus, 1979, 1 score (12 pages); Print (photocopy) Southern Music Instrumentation: For medium voice and piano Marked with duration and date of composition. (Box 24, Folder 0522)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Edges: a portrait of Robert Indiana, 1973, 1 score (5 pages); Print G. Schirmer Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings, including fingerings and accidentals. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 24, Folder 0523)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Etude for cello and piano: a portrait of Frederic James, 1966, 1 score (3 pages); Holograph (Ozalid copy) Instrumentation: For cello and piano Markings include fingerings and an alteration to measure 12. (Box 24, Folder 0524)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Four portraits: drawn from life, undated, 1 score (20 pages); Manuscript (Ozalid copy) Instrumentation: For cello and piano The small number of markings includes fingerings and dynamics. Transcription for cello and piano by Luigi Silva. Additional name: Silva, Luigi, 1903-1961 (Box 24, Folder 0525)
    Bugles and birds (Pablo Picasso) -- Tango lullaby (Flavie Alvares de Toledo) -- In a bird cage (Lise Deharme) -- Fanfare for France (Max Kenna)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Four saints in three acts. Selections, undated, 1 vocal score (14 leaves); Print (photocopy) G. Schirmer Instrumentation: Arranged for voices and piano Contains performance markings. Consists of pages 22-35 (Act 1). Found in a folder labeled Around the World with American Opera. (Box 24, Folder 0526)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Jay Rozen, 1984, 1 score (1 leaf); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For tuba and piano Includes changes to measure 6. (Box 24, Folder 0527)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 John Houseman: a double take, 1985, 2 scores (2 leaves each); Manuscript (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano One copy contains markings, including additional dynamics and fingerings. Found in folder labeled Virgil Thomson: The Last Portraits. 5 copies. (Box 24, Folder 0528)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Party pieces [by] Virgil Thomson, Henry Cowell, John Cage [and] Lou Harrison, undated, 1 score (15 pages); Print Edition Peters Instrumentation: Arranged for flute, clarinet, bassoon, horn, and piano Arranged by Robert Hughes. Signed by Mikhashoff. Photocopy of New York Times 12 December 1982 review of performance by Brooklyn Philharmonic attached inside back cover. Additional name: Cage, John; Harrison, Lou, 1917-2003; Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965 (Box 24, Folder 0529)
    Includes additional photocopy of a proof version marked Bassoon showing changes that were incorporated into the published version.
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Persistently pastoral: Aaron Copland, 1981, 1 score (4 leaves); Print (photocopy) Boosey & Hawkes Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration. Pages 41-44. (Box 24, Folder 0530)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Plough: suite for piano, 1936, 1 score (11 pages); Manuscript (ozalid copy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Markings include dynamics, phrase marks, and indications of takes for a recording session. Includes extra photocopied pages to facilitate page turns. (Box 24, Folder 0531)
    Prelude -- Cowboy songs -- Blues -- We're goin' to leave ol' Texas now
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Portrait of two, 1986, 1 score (12 pages) and 2 parts; Print G. Schirmer Instrumentation: For oboe, bassoon, and piano Score and parts contain performance markings, including a metronome marking. (Box 24, Folder 0532)
    Parts for oboe and bassoon.
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Serenade: for flute and violin, 1952, 1 score (7 pages); Print Southern Music Instrumentation: For flute and violin Contains just a few performance markings. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 24, Folder 0533)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Sonata da chiesa, undated, 1 score (19 pages) and 4 parts; Print Boosey & Hawkes Instrumentation: For clarinet, trumpet, viola, horn, and trombone Score and parts heavily marked for performance. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 24, Folder 0534)
    Parts for trumpet, clarinet, viola, trombone, and a photocopy of the score marked as horn part.
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Sonata for violin and piano, no. 1, 1941, 1 score (17 pages); Print Arrow Music Press Instrumentation: For violin and piano Contains performance markings, including fingerings and dynamics. (Box 24, Folder 0535)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Sonata no. 1 for piano, 1929, 1 score (20 pages); Manuscript (Ozalid copy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains small number of performance markings. (Box 24, Folder 0536)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 Ten easy pieces and a coda for piano, 1972, 1 score (8 pages); Print Southern Music Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. (Box 24, Folder 0537)
  - Trimble, Lester, 1923-1986 Four fragments: from Canterbury Tales, 1967, 1 score (42 pages) and 2 parts; Print (photocopy) C. F. Peters Instrumentation: For soprano, flute, clarinet, and harpsichord or piano Score and parts marked for performance. Score is photocopy, parts are originals. (Box 24, Folder 0538)
    Parts for clarinet and flute.
  - Turina, Joaquín, 1882-1949 Circus: suite for piano, 1960, 1 score (14 pages); Print Schott Instrumentation: For solo piano Performance markings on 5th piece, including fingerings. (Box 24, Folder 0539)
  - Valente, Augusto Five spirals (piano studies), 1989, 1 score (15 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings and an inscription from the composer to Mikhashoff. (Box 24, Folder 0540)
  - Various Romantic and modern piano concertos, 1940?, 1 score (111 pages); Print Longmans, Green and Company Instrumentation: For piano and orchestra Some of the works are marked for study purposes. Miniature scores; Missing pages 1-6. (Box 25, Folder 0541)
    Concerto in A minor, op. 54 / Robert Schumann -- Concerto in B-flat minor, op. 23 / Peter Ilich Tschaikowsky -- Concerto in E major [i.e. minor], op. 11; Concerto in F minor, op. 21 / Frédéric Chopin -- Concerto in G minor, op. 25 / Felix Mendelssohn -- Concerto in E-flat major; Concerto in A major / Franz Liszt -- Concerto in C minor, op. 35 / Dmitri Shostakovich -- Concerto in C minor, op. 18 / Sergei Rachmaninoff -- Symphonic variations / César Franck -- Concerto in A minor, op. 16 / Edvard Grieg -- Concerto in A minor, op. 17 / Ignace Jan Paderewski -- Concerto in G minor, op. 22 / Camille Saint-Saëns.
  - Various Toccata album for the piano, 1958, 1 score (146 pages); Print G. Schirmer Instrumentation: For solo piano Some works contain performance markings. Edited by Erno Balogh. Additional name: Balogh, Erno, 1897-1989 (Box 25, Folder 0542)
    Toccata on the sixth tone / Annibale Padovano -- Toccata on the second tone / Giovanni Gabrieli -- Toccata (G minor) / Girolamo Frescobaldi -- Toccata (A minor) / Johann Jacob Froberger -- Toccata (G major) / Dietrich Buxtehude -- Toccata (A major) / Henry Purcell [or J.S. Bach, or Michelangelo Rossi] -- Toccata (G major) / Alessandro Scarlatti -- Toccata in C-minor / Johann Sebastian Bach -- Toccata in G / Domenico Scarlatti -- Toccata (A major) / Pietro Domenico Paradisi -- Exercise in the form of a toccata / Francesco Pollini -- Toccata, op. 92 / Carl Czerny -- Toccata, op. 7 / Robert Schumann -- Toccata in E minor, op. 104 / Josef Rheinberger -- Toccata, op. 11 / Serge Prokofieff -- Toccata no. 2 / George Antheil -- Toccata / Aram Khachaturian -- Toccata, op. 1 / Lee Hoiby.
  - Vigeland, Nils 25o nocturne, 1989, 1 score (3 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains additional markings possibly in the composer's hand, including dynamics and pedal markings. Dedicated to Mikhashoff. (Box 25, Folder 0543)
  - Vigeland, Nils Ardor: a melodrama for narrator and piano, 1976, 1 score (13 leaves); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For speaker and piano Contains additional performance instructions. Dedicated to Mikhashoff and Paul Schmidt. Words from Ada by Vladimir Nabokov. Additional name: Nabokov, Vladimir Vladimirovich, 1899-1977 (Box 25, Folder 0544)
  - Vigeland, Nils Eleven pages: solo piano, 1983, 1 score (11 pages); Holograph (ozalid copy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains extensive performance markings. (Box 25, Folder 0545)
  - Vigeland, Nils Mnemosyne, 1987, 2 scores (5 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Scores marked First version and Revised, with first version marked with duration. (Box 25, Folder 0546)
  - Vigeland, Nils Sonata for piano (1969), 1969, 1 score (15 pages); Holograph (ink and pencil) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains some corrections and changes. (Box 25, Folder 0547)
  - Villa-Lobos, Heitor Suite pour chant et violon, 1925, 1 score (12 pages); Print (photocopy) Max Eschig Instrumentation: For soprano and violin Contains performance markings, including fingerings and bowings. Texts by Mario de Andrade. Additional name: Andrade, Mario de, 1893-1945 (Box 25, Folder 0548)
    1. A menina e a cançâo = La Fillette et la chanson / poème de Mario de Andrade -- 2. Quéro ser alégre = Je veux être gaie -- 3. Sertaneja =La campagnarde du Brésil.
  - Vivaldi, Antonio, 1678-1741 Concerto in re minore: per violino, flauto, fagotto e basso continuo, 1962, 1 score (8 pages) and 2 parts; Print (photocopy) G. Ricordi Instrumentation: For violin, flute, bassoon, and basso continuo Score and parts marked for performance Includes manuscript bassoon part and violin part created from lines cut from photocopy of full score. (Box 25, Folder 0549)
  - Walton, William, 1902-1983 Three songs, 1960, 1 score (18 pages); Print Oxford University Press Instrumentation: For voice and piano Contains performance markings in the piano part, including fingerings. Texts by Edith Sitwell. Additional name: Sitwell, Edith, 1887-1964 (Box 25, Folder 0550)
  - Ware, Peter, 1951- Night rainbow: for clarinet, viola and piano, 1983, 1 score (20 pages), 1 score (8 leaves) and 1 part (4 leaves); Holograph (photocopy) Acoma Composer's Edition Instrumentation: For clarinet, viola and piano Scores and part marked for performance. (Box 25, Folder 0551)
    1 spiral bound score (1984), 1 photocopy score (earlier version, 1983), and 1 part for piano.
  - Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826 Trio, piano, flute, violoncello, op. 63, G minor, 1947, 1 score (23 pages) and 2 parts; Print International Music Instrumentation: For flute or violin, cello, and piano Score and parts marked for performance, including fingerings and bowings. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 25, Folder 0552)
    Parts for cello, and flute or violin.
  - Webern, Anton, 1883-1945 Five sacred songs. No. 4: Mein Weg geht jetzt vorüber, 1924, 1 part (1 leaf); Print (photocopy) Universal Edition Instrumentation: For voice and instrumental ensemble Flute part with clarinet part written in on added line. (Box 25, Folder 0553)
  - Webern, Anton, 1883-1945 Kinderstück, 1967, 1 score (2 leaves); Print (photocopy) Carl Fischer Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration. (Box 25, Folder 0554)
  - Webern, Anton, 1883-1945 Variationen für Klavier op. 27, 1937, 1 score (11 pages); Print Universal Edition Instrumentation: For solo piano First page of score marked for performance; elsewhere the score is marked with row forms, possibly by Allen Sapp. Signed by Allen Sapp. (Box 25, Folder 0555)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 34, 1967, 1 score (6 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings, including measure groupings and durations. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0556)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 53, undated, 1 score (3 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains some performance markings and duration. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0557)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 54, 1972, 1 score (2 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0558)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 55, 1972, 1 score (2 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Caption inscription: "From Busoni (Dr. Faustus). Faust in his study …" Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0559)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 56, 1972, 1 score (2 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration. Caption: "Mahler 5 scherzo…" Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0560)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 57, 1973, 1 score (2 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0561)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 58, 1973, 1 score (3 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration. Additional 13 measures of manuscript music on page 3. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0562)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 59, 1973, 1 score (3 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration. Caption: "Medtner G minor sonata". Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0563)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 62, 1973, 1 score (3 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0564)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 64, 1973, 1 score (5 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0565)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonatas no. 65, 68, 69, 1973, 3 scores (2 leaves each); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0566)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 76, 1973, 1 score (6 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0567)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 81, 1973, 1 score (8 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0568)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 82, 1973, 1 score (4 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0569)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 84, 1973, 1 score (5 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0570)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 86, 1973, 1 score (2 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings, including fingerings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0571)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 87, 1973, 1 score (4 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0572)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 89, 1973, 1 score (10 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0573)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 90, 1973, 1 score (16 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Caption: "Midsummer night's dream Act II". Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0574)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 91, 1976, 1 score (11 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with metronome marking. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0575)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 95, 1977, 1 score (7 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with metronome marking and some additional performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0576)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 98, 1978, 1 score (4 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with metronome markings and some descriptive notes. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0577)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 101, 1980, 1 score (4 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0578)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 102, 1980, 1 score (5 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0579)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 103, 1980, 1 score (5 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 25, Folder 0580)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 104, 1980, 1 score (5 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Margin inscription: "Mahler 6th last mvt.". Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 26, Folder 0581)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 105, 1980, 1 score (5 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Marked with duration and some performance markings. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 26, Folder 0582)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 106, 1980, 1 score (5 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano All of the markings appear to be on the original not the photocopy. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 26, Folder 0583)
  - White, John, 1936- Piano sonata no. 108, 1983, 1 score (3 pages); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. Dedicated to Mikhashoff. Originally kept in a folder labeled John White Piano Sonatas. They are now stored in 35 individual folders. (Box 26, Folder 0584)
  - Winther, Terje, 1963- Bor, 1991, 1 score (19 pages); Print (manuscript copy) Norsk Musikkinformasion Instrumentation: For oboe/WX-7 + MIDI-sounds, piano/MIDI keyboard + MIDI sounds, Macintosh computer + MIDI-sounds + analogs Contains some performance markings. (Box 26, Folder 0585)
  - Wolff, Christian, 1934- Braverman music, undated, 1 score (16 leaves); Holograph (photocopy) Instrumentation: For minimum of 4 unspecified instruments Contains performance markings and indications for instrumentation. (Box 26, Folder 0586)
  - Wolff, Christian, 1934- Bread and roses: piano solo, undated, 1 score (5 pages); Print (manuscript reproduction) C. F. Peters Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. Signed by Mikhashoff. Original song, Bread and roses, attached to verso of front cover. Program note consisting of letter from Wolff to pianist Ursula Oppens attached facing page 1 of the music. (Box 26, Folder 0587)
  - Wolff, Christian, 1934- For piano I, 1964, 1 score (12 pages); Print C. F. Peters Instrumentation: For solo piano Extensively marked for performance, including time signatures. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 26, Folder 0588)
  - Wolff, Christian, 1934- Snowdrop, 1970, 2 scores (9 leaves each); Manuscript (photocopy) C. F. Peters Instrumentation: For harpsichord and/or other instruments Marked for performance. 2 copies. (Box 26, Folder 0589)
  - Wolff, Christian, 1934- Three studies, 1976, 1 score (5 pages); Holograph (reproduction) C. F. Peters Instrumentation: For solo piano Contains performance markings. Signed by Mikhashoff. (Box 26, Folder 0590)
  - Wuorinen, Charles Bearbeitungen über Das Glogauer Liederbuch, 1971, 3 scores (24 pages each); Manuscript (reproduction) C. F. Peters Instrumentation: For flute (piccolo), clarinet (bass clarinet), violin, and contrabass (or cello) Contains performance markings. Two scores are photocopies, one marked for use as violin part, the other is marked for use as a cello part, with the line added to the score written from the bass line. (Box 26, Folder 0591)
  - Wyschnegradsky, Ivan, 1893-1979 2 compositions: op. 46. I. en sìxièmes de ton pour trois pianos, 1979, 2 scores (11 pages each); Holograph (ink) Instrumentation: For three pianos Photocopy score marked for performance; inscription from the composer to Mikhashoff in caption. One copy is the original ink manuscript, the other is a photocopy. (Box 26, Folder 0592)
  - Wyschnegradsky, Ivan, 1893-1979 Étude sur les mouvements rotatoires: op. 45, undated, 1 score (13 pages) and 2 parts (10 pages each); Holograph (ozalid copy) Instrumentation: For two pianos tuned a quarter tone apart, 4 hands Score is marked for performance, including time signatures, corrections, and a manuscript insert attached. The parts are also marked for performance. (Box 26, Folder 0593)
    Parts for Piano I and II.